# FERNANDA Thiesen

Front end developer

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

A front-end developer with more than 20 years of experience in working as a self-employed and independent marketing and graphic design professional. I use my curious mind, attention to detail and persistence to innovate and solve problems in order to build intuitive and accessible websites and applications. I am looking to explore new opportunities that help me grow as a developer.

### **SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

- HTML5, CSS, SCSS
- · Responsive Design
- JavaScript (ES6+), jQuery and React
- Working with RESTful APIs and Firebase
- Website accessibility requirements
- Version control & collaboration using Git and GitHub
- Paired programming and teambased development
- Project scope management
- Decision maker
- Team player
- Innovator

### **CONTACT DETAILS**

Email: fcthiesen@gmail.com

Phone: 647 818 7114
Portfolio: ferncodes.com
GitHub: github.com/fthiesen

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/fernanda-

thiesen

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **ANONYMOUS VOTING**

HTML5, SCSS, Firebase, React

An app that allows anyone to create a polling room and share the link with the participants. The users can vote and see the results. LINK

#### **MUST WATCH**

HTML5, SCSS, API, Firebase, React

A movie recommendation app built with React, Firebase and the OMDb API.  $\ensuremath{\mathsf{LINK}}$ 

#### **BOAT RIDE ADVENTURES**

HTML5, SCSS, Javascript

A multi-page website PSD to HTML and CSS conversion made with SCSS and a little Javascript to add an off-canvas mobile menu. LINK

#### **EDUCATION**

## WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE (2021)

Juno College of Technology, Canada

## INTRO TO WEB DEVELOPMENT AND JAVASCRIPT FUNDAMENTALS (2020-2021)

Juno College of Technology, Canada

## BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN SOCIAL COMMUNICATIONS AND MARKETING (2001)

FACHA - Faculdades Integradas Hélio Alonso, Brazil

## TECHNICAL SCHOOL CERTIFICATE IN ADVERTISING (1997)

ETEC - Escola Técnica de Comunicação, Brazil

### **EXPERIENCE**

## FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER AND MARKETER (1999-2021)

Brazil, Canada

- Worked both individually and with hosting support teams to troubleshoot WordPress and server issues for clients.
- Engaged with hundreds of small business owners and managers, uncovering their needs and suggesting marketing and graphic design ideas as well as WordPress functionalities and website solutions.

## FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER, EDITOR-IN-CHIEF, MARKETER (2009-2021)

#### OiCanada Digital Magazine, Canada

- Created several designs over the years, keeping a fresh look for the readers, and customized WordPress themes to match the magazine's brand guidelines.
- Engaged with several advertisers, understanding their campaign goals to help them promote their businesses to the magazine's audience and generate leads through banner ads, paid content, landing pages, email marketing and social media marketing.
- Developed the magazine from scratch and reached a substantial average of 100,00 page views per month in 2016, having published more than 1,500 pieces